# **CURRICULUM VITAE**

### **Personal Information**

Full name: Le Minh Nguyen (Nguyễn Lê Minh)

Nationality: Vietnamese Date of Birth: 10/03/1993

Gender: Male

Marital status: Single Phone: 0164 617 4739

Email: minhnguyen31093@gmail.com

Languages: Vietnamese (Native), English (Intermediate)

Address: 65 – Yersin Street – Cau Ong Lanh Ward – District 1 – HCMC.

My Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/minhnguyen31093

My Github: https://github.com/minhnguyen31093

My Youtube Channel: https://www.youtube.com/user/EternalUnlimitedTear

### **Education**

Information Technology

Faculty of Electronics and Computer Science Engineering

2011 - 2014 Cao Thang Technical College, Ho Chi Minh City, Viet Nam

# **Summary**

I am a good skilled developer working as Android Developer for more than one year and a half. Mobile development is my favorite. Not only individual working, but also team working is suitable for me. I like to study the library and development of new library in Android. The next time, I will learn IOS and Window Phone. I am willing to learn new technologies and techniques to overcome challenges in my field of work. Soft skills, such as: information searching and analyzing, solving problems, are other fantastic abilities of mine.

### **Skills**

- Soft Skills
  - Teamwork, Manage time, Organizational effectiveness
  - English: Communicate, discuss in groups, read English documents

### Programming Skills

- Language: C#, HTML, CSS, Java
- o Database: SQLite, ORMLite, MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server
- Network: JSON, XML, REST API, Dropbox API, Facebook API, Twitter API, Google API, Parse API
- Software Design: OOP, Design Pattern
- SDK: ASP.NET, JavaDevelopment: Android
- Software
  - Platforms: Windows
  - IDE and Tools: Eclipse, Netbeans, Visual Studio, Android Studio, MySQL Workbench, Microsoft SQL Server, Flash, Photoshop, Google, Corel Studio, 3DS Max.

# **Experience**

9/2015 – Now Software Engineer at HiP

6/2014 – 7/2015 Software Engineer at Agilsun Co., LTD

### 9/2015 – Now: Lich Van Nien New

- Lich Van Nien help you to know the Zodiac time, CanChi, Good and Bad day, Start Direction or what should and shouldn't do in your chosen day. It also help you to manage information with day and month easier.
- In this project I learned: Infinite Viewpager, Transform animation, Dialog from bottom, Calculate Lunar day, Wheel view, newest Facebook API, Facebook Audience Network, Parse push notification, Google Plus, Google Analytics, Google Location Services, Alarm manager, Ringtone manager, Volley, Okhttp, Gson, ActiveAndroid.

# 8/2015 - 9/2015: The KidzGrow App

- The KidzGrow App is the most complete child development tool for parents and caregivers.
- In this project I learned: Viewpager Intro, Picasso

• Library I created: https://github.com/minhnguyen31093/Countries-Picker

#### 6/2015 – 7/2015: Retotus

• In this project I learned: Fragment backstack

### 3/2015 - 5/2015: Ludi

- Ludi help you find and receive detailed information of ongoing and upcoming events within an appropriate radius of your current location.
- Mobile app: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.agilsun.ludi">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.agilsun.ludi</a>
- In this project I learned: Google Map API, Google Cloud Message, Push notification, Data storage, Twitter API, Location Service, Get contacts, Scan QR code, Horizontalscrollview snap to page, Pie Chart.

### 12/2014 - 2/2015: TuoiThoDuDoi

- Read comics from <u>TuoiThoDuDoi.com</u>
  Comics are translated from TuoiThoDuDoi team.
  - Mobile app:

https://www.dropbox.com/s/hchr726e5cdxqgd/04062015TuoiThoDuDoi.apk?dl=1

• In this project I learned: Facebook API, Google Admob, Increase performance, Gridview pull to refresh and load more, Directional Viewpager, Multi Screen support.

# 10/2014 - 11/2014: ImmaNjoy

- ImmaNjoy is an application that makes it easy to create questionnaire, checklist and article of new style unprecedented.
  - Mobile app: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.sharedsys.ImmaNjoy
- In this project I learned: REST API, JSON, Listview pull to refresh and load more, Expandable Listview, Custom UI.

#### 7/2014 - 9/2014: Camera Animal

- A funny app to create funny photos, use funny animal heads. User requirement: funny is a must!
- In this project I learned: Image progress, Android handle.

## **Project References**

- Reminiscent: includes Reminder, Alarm, Sticky Note, Schedule, Favorite files, folders, videos, music, websites, Spending Management with chart, English and Vietnamese Language <a href="https://github.com/minhnguyen31093/Reminiscent">https://github.com/minhnguyen31093/Reminiscent</a>
- Hotel Management <a href="https://github.com/minhnguyen31093/Hotel-Management">https://github.com/minhnguyen31093/Hotel-Management</a>

## **Hobbies & Interests**

- Reading books: Harry Potter, Light Novel,...
- Listen to music: Pop, Traditional.
- Playing games: Final Fantasy Series, GTA Series,...
- Watching Movies: Marvel Series, Once Upon A Time,...
- Travel: Hue, Ha Noi, Nha Trang, Da Lat,...